Hello, all my friends, and welcome again to the complete data structure and algorithms course in exercise
number seven.
You are asked to write a function that deletes a specific node from circular link at list.
So we are given a key or data that it is contained in the node that we are going to delete and we search
engine linkage list for this node and we delete it.
There are many conditions or many like ways or many possibilities that we should cover in deleting silk.
Concentrate with me, guys.
I will create a method called.
Delete so public static.
Note, delete, note and take into putting me through the head and import key.
So we are going to create this method that.
Took into perimeter, the note had that we are going to start that specified the start and the head
position of the link list, and we will traverse this through all this linked list and to find the key.
If it is found, then we are going to delete it and we should make correction for the links that it
is that it is contained inside this thing at list or the note that we have deleted.
OK.
If it does not exist, we should also cover this statement.
And also, if it is the head, we should cover the state and so on.
These possibilities, we are going to cover them and this coating.
So we start check.
I will put the comments here in order to understand everything.
One.
Check if empty list how to check if this empty list is very simple.
If had to have equal to now, if we are specifying and the head is null, then the list is not so returned.
Not because we are returning a note.
We should specify a handwritten note note.
So this note will be returned as not now searching through searching for for the specific
note to be deleted.
How to do that note current equal to health.
Let me start by creating a new node.
This, called had its gold card and it points to the head and the from head.
We need to move this note and to create and search for this specific gate.
Another node that I need is to call the previous and it is in you node, you know, and we will specify
its data later on.
So.
While.
Current DOT data does not equal to key if we didn't found the key, then make this point.
Go ahead and loop through the next.
How to move the cursor.
It's very simple.
We have done this many times current the index equal, equal to head check.
It is ahead because we are working with a circular link at least, and we start searching if we found
that the head is equal to the next point.
So if we reached the last of the at the end of the link, a circular link, at least the last note of
the circular link at least will point to the first would point to the head.
So we are checking that if current dot next equal to had, then we have reached the end of the circular
link at least.
Zen System dot out dot Brent Allen given node is not in there and is not in that list, given node is
not found or given key.
Given data of known
or given note, it's good.
OK.
And then break from this loop.
Otherwise, otherwise, we are going to see how to move the cursor previous, current and the current
now if what's the current next?
OK, we are jumping the cursor.
We are moving it to the next one and we have specified pretty equal to that.
OK, now let me check if the node is only.
Note it is only contained in the list.
So the third case that we should cover is only one node is found, is presented or is created or is
in that link.
This
if current equal equal to head and Gerhard and the next equal equal to had then had equal to null
and return and had.
OK.
Let me check if.
If more than one node check, if it is the first note, OK, I told you that you should cover many scenarios.
The first one, if it is laying an empty list, the second one, we are searching for it, if it is
not found or if it is found or not.
And the link at least the third scenario is only one node is in the list.
The fourth scenario is more than one node, but we are checking if it is the first.
OK, if it is, check, check if it is ahead.
So if current goes, we have inserted it in that vacheron.
If had had if had equal to that current, then previous equal to had made the previous equal to had.
And while previous, we are talking here with many nodes, but it is the case of it is had.
So we are going to delete ahead.
You insert a key and this key refers to the head of the linked list.
So then we are going to make y loop that points to the next and had now be equal to the current dog
next.
OK.
And the brave the next equal to had.
No.
Health if.
Let me check another thing, the fifth scenario, if it is the last note.
If it is the last.
Know what we will do as if governance the next equal, equal to have these guys how to check if it is
a last note, then brave the next equal to hand.
Otherwise, we are checking if it is found, but that there's not had not a head or.
Or a last note.
It is in between.
How to do that, it is very simple by making else.
You see, guys, how many scenarios you should cover because you becoming a professional coder, you
should think about all the possibilities and you are asked about them in the university and in their
interviews.
If you should cover all of these.
You are astute to see if you cover to them.
OK.
And if you think about all the possibilities, then it will return in that.
OK?
This is that.
No.
They're returning type of that elite note, and this is the method that we have created.
They take it into parameters and no tab and we start searching for that key.
If it is found, if we are, we have many possibilities.
It may be the head.
So we are going to make this.
If we is know that we are going to search for is a last note, so we are going to do this.
And if it is in between, then we are going to do this.
If then know that we are going to search for it, for the specific key for it, it contains that data
or not, or it is a note in the inside the linked list, then it is not found in the link at less than
we do this.
OK.
And if it is an empty list, we will do this.
You see, guys, how many scenarios that you should that we should cover?
Now let's run.
And see two, three, four one six five.
I need to delete the key number four, so I will use node or I will specify here, you know, node node
find node seven people to use new node.
And here in new Note seven equal to delete note and we search for the have had passed the hand and we
passed the key that you are going to delete if there's four.
That's redundancy.
If it's disappeared and there we go.
This is the link, at least circle and marketplace and we have successfully deleted number four.
OK.
It's very simple.
I hope you do me a favor.
Read us our five stars on Udemy.